It's nothing personal. It's just their job.
Monsters, Inc. is a animation, comedy, family film directed by Pete Docter.
Lovable Sulley and his wisecracking sidekick Mike Wazowski are the top scare team
at Monsters, Inc., the scream-processing factory in Monstropolis.
When a little girl named Boo wanders into their world, it's the monsters who are scared silly,
and it's up to Sulley and Mike to keep her out of sight and get her back home.
Sullivan (voice), played by John Goodman.
Mike (voice), played by Billy Crystal.
Boo (voice), played by Mary Gibbs.
Randall (voice), played by Steve Buscemi.
Waternoose (voice), played by James Coburn.
Celia (voice), played by Jennifer Tilly.
Monsters, Inc.
(also known as Monsters, Incorporated) is a 2001 American animated comedy film produced by Pixar Animation Studios for Walt Disney
Pictures, and starring the voices of John Goodman, Billy Crystal, Steve Buscemi, James Coburn, Jennifer Tilly, and Mary Gibbs.
Directed by Pete Docter, and written by Andrew Stanton and Daniel
Gerson, the film centers on two monsters, the hairy James P.
"Sulley" Sullivan (Goodman) and his one-eyed partner and best friend Mike Wazowski (Crystal), who are employed at
the titular energy-producing factory Monsters, Inc., which generates power by scaring human children.
However, the monster world believes that the children are toxic, and when a little human girl, Boo
(Gibbs), sneaks into the factory, the duo must safely return her home while evading discovery.
Docter began developing the film in 1996, following an idea conceived in 1994 when Toy Story (1995) was nearing completion, and
wrote the story with Jill Culton, Jeff Pidgeon and Ralph Eggleston, while Stanton wrote the screenplay with Gerson.
The characters went through many incarnations over the
film's five-year production process.
The technical team and animators found new ways to simulate
fur and cloth realistically for the film.
Randy Newman, who composed the music for Pixar's three prior
films, returned to compose the score for its fourth.
Monsters, Inc.
premiered at the El Capitan Theatre in Los Angeles on October 28, 2001, and
was released in theaters in the United States on November 2.
Upon its release, it received critical acclaim and was a commercial success, grossing over
$528 million worldwide to become the third-highest-grossing film of 2001.
The film won the Academy Award for Best Original Song for "If I Didn't Have You" and was nominated for the
inaugural award for Best Animated Feature, as well as Best Original Score and Best Sound Editing.
Monsters, Inc.
saw a 3D re-release in theaters in December 2012.
A prequel titled Monsters University, directed by Dan
Scanlon, was released in June 2013.
A sequel series titled Monsters at Work premiered on Disney+ in July 2021.
The film explores themes of monster, panic, cheating, kidnapping, door.
The tone is lighthearted.